Guide to the Lance R. Bell papers, 1947-2017 and undated RL.11533
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lance R. Bell papers
1947-2017 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Bell, Lance R.
RL.11533
3.0 Linear Feet
Outdoor advertising executive with Southern Outdoor Markets and Associates of the Bell Company firms, based in Atlanta, Ga. Collection includes trade publications, awards booklets, reprints and other printed materials, slides, photographs, audiocassettes and 35mm films. Companies represented include the Associates of the Bell Company; Foote Cone & Belding; Foster & Kleiser; Institute of Outdoor Advertising; Outdoor Advertising Association of America; Outdoor Advertising Incorporated; Southern Outdoor Markets. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: General Files; Slides; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Outdoor advertising executive with Southern Outdoor Markets and Associates of the Bell Company firms, based in Atlanta, Ga. Graduate, University of Missouri School of Journalism; Account Executive, Institute of Outdoor Advertising 1960; Executive Sales Manager, Outdoor Advertising Inc. 1964; founder and President, Southern Outdoor Markets 1965, renamed Associates of the Bell Company (ABC) 1974; awarded Ray Vahue Award/Marketing Award of Merit by OAAA 1985; ABC acquired by Bill Wilkins 1987, renamed Wilkins Media Company 1999.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed to researchers until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lance R. Bell papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center Collections:
Garrett Orr papers; Outdoor Advertising Association of America Archives; Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library; Wilkins Media Company records
Collection Overview
Collection includes trade publications, awards booklets, reprints and other printed materials, slides, photographs, audiocassettes and 35mm films. Companies represented include the Associates of the Bell Company; Foote Cone & Belding; Foster & Kleiser; Institute of Outdoor Advertising; Outdoor Advertising Association of America; Outdoor Advertising Incorporated; Southern Outdoor Markets. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising, Outdoor; Advertising executives -- United States; Billboards -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Outdoor Advertising Association of America; Institute of Outdoor Advertising; Foster and Kleiser Company; Foote, Cone & Belding
- General Files, 1965-2017 and undated; 1
  - Associates of the Bell Company--Forms, stationery, etc., 1973 and undated; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bell biographical information, 1987-2017 (Box 1)
  - Creative Guide to Outdoor Advertising, undated (Box 1)
  - Distance and legibility cards, undated (Box 1)
  - Earl Nightingale--Who's the Boss?, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Foote, Cone & Belding--Enjoy the Great Outdoors, undated (Box 1)
  - Foster & Kleiser--Glossary of outdoor advertising terms, undated (Box 1)
  - Health Maintenance Organization (HMO) billboard designs, undated (Box 5)
  - Institute of Outdoor Advertising (IOA)--33rd National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Institute of Outdoor Advertising (IOA)--34th National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Institute of Outdoor Advertising (IOA)--36th National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Institute of Outdoor Advertising (IOA)--38th Outdoor Advertising Competition, 1970 (Box 1)
  - KC Coatings--Color Selector, undated (Box 1)
  - Kubin-Nicholson--Outdoor Advertising Sizes and Production Requirements, undated (Box 1)
  - Operational Guidelines in the Outdoor Medium, undated (Box 1)
  - Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA)--1982 OBIE Awards (Box 1)
  - Outdoor Advertising Incorporated (OAI)--Poster Annual, 1947-1962 (Box 5)
  - Outdoor Advertising Myths and Facts, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor advertising sales representatives list, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs--England, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs--Mexico, undated (Box 1)
  - Research/Statistics, 1977-1985 (Box 1)
- Slides, 1963-1986 and undated; 2
  - 36th, 39th outdoor awards, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
  - 37th outdoor awards, 1969 (Box 1)
  - 38th outdoor awards, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - 39th outdoor awards, 1971 (Box 1)
  - A night out in the hills, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Airplanes, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Alabama Outdoor--Take a Look at Outdoor, undated (Box 2)
  - Automotive, 1967-1979 (Box 2)
  - Automotive presentations, 1960-1969 (Box 2)
  - Award presentation, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bank presentations, 1975 and undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Bank presentation--Outdoor for Banks, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Banks, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
  - Bravo, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Creative art, 1970-1976 (Box 2)
  - Creative surge, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Food and beverage, 1966-1979 (Box 2)
  - Insurance, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Insurance--Integon, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Insurance--Life of Georgia, 1973 (Box 2)
  - IOA art awards, 1966 (Box 3)
  - IOA--Go By Outdoor presentation, undated (Box 3)
  - Land Development Ordinance (LDO), Jacksonville, Fla. Rotary Plan, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Lawn and garden, agriculture, 1973-1978 (Box 3)
  - Liquor presentation, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Location shots, 1967-1979 (Box 3)
  - Macon, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Martin Outdoor (Tampa, Fla.), 1973 (Box 3)
  - Media (Newspaper, radio, television), 1974-1979 (Box 3)
  - Media mix presentation, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Mexico, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-1986; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - OAI--Outdoor for Agricultural Products presentation, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Presentation slides, miscellaneous, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Presentation--Coca-Cola, undated (Box 3)
  - Presentations, 1966-1975 (Box 4)
  - Public service, personal, political, 1970s-1980 (Box 4)
  - Reach and Frequency presentation, 1973-1981 (Box 4)
  - Real estate, 1974-1977 (Box 4)
  - Restaurants, 1973-1981 (Box 4)
  - Retail, miscellaneous consumer goods and services, 1975-1979 (Box 4)
  - Retail--Hastings, undated (Box 4)
  - Slides from Henderson, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Supermarket presentation, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Supermarket--Winn-Dixie, undated (Box 4)
  - Testa presentations, 1963-1971; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - This is Outdoor presentations, 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Tobacco, 1966-1973 (Box 4)
  - Travel and entertainment, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
  - Washington, D.C., 1966 (Box 4)
  - Working Woman presentation, undated (Box 4)
  - What Outdoor Can and Cannot Do presentation, undated (Box 4)
- Audiovisual Materials, Undated; 3
  - Go Buy Outdoor audiocassette, undated (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11533-CS-001)
  - It Pays to Be Creative (Foster & Kleiser) audiocassette, undated (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11533-CS-002)
  - The Working Woman audiocassette, undated (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11533-CS-003)
  - OAI--The Wonderful World of Signs 35mm filmstrip, undated (Box 5, Film RL11533-F35-001)
  - OAI--The Wonderful World of Signs 35mm filmstrip, undated (Box 5, Film RL11533-F35-002)